crmondemand.com 2006-12-08

# Privacy Statement

| **WORLDWIDE PRICING**  
---  
**€ 55 month/user *** | **£50 month/user * ** | **$70 month/user ***  
|  Austria  
Belgium  
Denmark  
Finland  
France  
Germany  
Ireland  
|  Italy  
Netherlands  
Norway  
Portugal  
Spain  
Sweden  
Switzerland  
---|---  
United Kingdom  
|  All other countries  
  
***** Based on a 12-month subscription  
  
BMC Monitoring, Do Not Remove!

  | 

As the leading provider of Customer Relationship Management software and solutions, Oracle Corporation and our subsidiaries (collectively, "Oracle" or "we") understand the importance of the privacy of personal information. We are committed to making sure you understand how carefully we handle any personal information you may provide to us. By "personal information," we mean information that relates specifically to you as a person, such as your name, address, phone number or email address. Oracle is committed to protecting your privacy and we have created this Privacy Statement to describe and explain our practices concerning personal information we collect on our web sites.

In an effort to make it easy for you to find the information you need, we have organized this Privacy Statement into the following sections:

  1. TRUSTe Certification
  2. EU Safe Harbor
  3. Web Sites Covered by this Privacy Statement
  4. The Personal Information We Collect.
  5. How We Use the Personal Information We Collect
  6. Sharing the Personal Information We Collect
  7. Choices Regarding Your Personal Information
  8. Access to Your Personal Information
  9. Security
  10. Key Oracle Products and Personal Information
  11. Changes to this Privacy Statement
  12. Contact Us

### TRUSTe Certification

Oracle is a licensee of the TRUSTe Privacy Program. TRUSTe is an independent, non-profit organization whose mission is to build users' trust and confidence in the Internet by promoting the use of fair information practices. This Privacy Statement covers the Oracle web sites identified below. Because Oracle wants to demonstrate its commitment to your privacy, it has agreed to disclose its information practices and have its privacy practices reviewed for compliance by TRUSTe.

If you have questions or concerns regarding this Privacy Statement, you should first contact Oracle directly. Send an email with the subject heading, "Privacy Statement Question," to [privacy_ww@oracle.com](mailto:privacy_ww@oracle.com), or send a letter to the mailing address set forth at the end of this Privacy Statement. Oracle will attempt to respond to your request as quickly as possible. If you do not receive acknowledgement of your inquiry or your inquiry has not been satisfactorily addressed, however, you should then contact TRUSTe at [www.truste.org/consumers/watchdog_complaint.php](http://www.truste.org/consumers/watchdog_complaint.php). TRUSTe will then serve as a liaison to resolve your concerns.

The TRUSTe program covers only information that is collected through this web site, and does not cover information that may be collected through software downloaded, if any, from this site.

### European Union Safe Harbor

Oracle complies with the European Union Safe Harbor framework as set forth by the U.S Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of data from the European Union.

### Web Sites Covered by this Privacy Statement

This privacy statement covers [www.siebel.com](http://www.siebel.com/) and the following related web sites owned and operated by Oracle: [www.siebeluniversity.siebel.com](http://www.siebeluniversity.siebel.com/), [www.crmondemand.com](http://www.crmondemand.com/), [www.contactondemand.com](http://www.contactondemand.com/), [www.ebusiness.siebel.com](http://www.ebusiness.siebel.com/), [www.upshot.com](http://www.upshot.com/), and [www.egovclub.org](http://www.egovclub.org/), as well as the following co-branded partner sites: [www.siebel-sun.com and www.siebel-hp.com](http://www.siebel-sun.com%20and%20www.siebel-hp.com/). 

**Links to Other Sites.** Some of our web sites contain links to other sites that are not owned or controlled by Oracle. Please be aware that this Privacy Statement applies only to personal information collected by Oracle on its web sites. Oracle is not responsible for the privacy practices of third party web sites, and we do not endorse or make any representations about these third party sites. We encourage you to be aware when you leave a Oracle web site and to read the privacy statements of every web site that collects personal information. 

### The Personal Information We Collect

In order to better serve our customers and those interested in our products and services, Oracle may collect personal and non-personal information through our web sites. The submission of personal information, however, is voluntary.

Oracle's web sites are designed to allow you to visit them anonymously to learn about the company, our products and many of our customer success stories without disclosing personal information. If you request certain information or items, however, like a product demonstration or a white paper, we will ask you for personal information that allows us to respond effectively to your request. The information we request is your name, address, job title, company name, email address and phone number. Also, to ensure the accuracy and completeness of our information, and serve you better, we may periodically use third party information to validate the company name and address information you provide us.

We may collect credit card information from you if you elect to purchase training products or services at [www.siebeluniversity.com](http://www.siebeluniversity.com/), or if you purchase our Siebel CRM On Demand service through [www.crmondemand.com](http://www.crmondemand.com/). In either case, we use your credit card information only to process your purchase through a credit card processor and we use secure socket layer ("SSL") technology to encrypt your credit card number when we communicate it to the processor. We do not retain your credit card information after your order is processed.

**The Oracle Online Community.** If you sign up to use the Oracle Online Community, you will be able to create a user profile. Other users will not be able to see personal information about you on the Oracle Online Community, unless you include such information in your login name, or in a posting. When you use the Oracle Online Community, or any other forums, message boards, messages, posts, replies and discussion threads on a Oracle web site, you should be aware that any personal information you submit there can be read, collected, or used by other users of these forums and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. As a result, the terms of service for the Oracle Online Community state that members or users of the Oracle Online Community may not submit personal information within messages. Oracle is not responsible for members or users who violate the terms of service or otherwise choose to submit personal information on the Oracle Online Community.

**Cookies and other non-personal information.** As is true of most web sites, we automatically gather certain non-personal information from visitors to our web sites and store that information in log files. This information includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data. We use this information, which does not identify individual users, to analyze trends, to administer the site, to track users' movements around the site, and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We do not link this automatically-collected data to personal information. Also, our "Shopping Cart" feature on [www.siebeluniversity.com](http://www.siebeluniversity.com/) does not use cookies.

In addition, we use session ID cookies on our web sites. A session ID cookie expires when you close your browser. We use the information stored in these session cookies to identify returning visitors and siebel.com Passport users. You may navigate through our web sites if you have chosen to reject cookies in your browser settings, but your ability to use some areas may be limited.

We use a third-party tracking service that uses cookies to track only non-personal information about visitors to our web sites. This service allows us to gather general web traffic patterns and behaviors, but users are not tracked individually and their personal information is not linked to the tracking results.

### How We Use the Personal Information We Collect

We collect personal information on our web sites for various purposes, including: 

  * To contact a customer about the services available on our web sites, as well as other products or services that we think may be of interest.
  * To obtain feedback through surveys regarding our products, our web sites, or other aspects of our business.
  * To send promotional materials.
  * To provide our free email newsletter.
  * To perform transactions through Oracle University, such as the purchase of training.
  * To fulfill requested services such as a demo, a course, or a support request.

When we request personal information from you, we give you the opportunity to 'opt-out' of having your personal information used for marketing purposes. For example, if you create a Siebel.com Passport on one of our web sites but do not wish to receive any additional marketing material from us, you can indicate this preference on the registration page when you register your Passport or on your Passport profile at any time afterward. Also, if you no longer wish to receive our newsletter or other promotional communications, you may opt-out of receiving them by following the instructions included in each newsletter or communication, or by emailing us at [privacy_ww@oracle.com](mailto:privacy_ww@oracle.com).

**Email a Friend.** If you choose to refer a friend or colleague to one of our web sites, we will ask for your friend or colleague's name and email address, and we automatically send a one-time email inviting your friend to visit the feature of the site you have recommended. Oracle stores your colleague's email address for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email and tracking the success of our referral program. Your friend may contact us at [privacy_ww@oracle.com](mailto:privacy_ww@oracle.com) to request that we remove his or her personal information from our database.

### Sharing the Personal Information We Collect

Where necessary, we may use a third party service provider to collect, process, store, or otherwise handle information on our behalf. Such third party providers include credit card processors, contractors, lead qualification firms, and other providers of marketing services.

**Oracle partners.** Oracle has established partnerships with other businesses in order to provide our customers with the best service and overall experience possible. Working with these partners allows Oracle to offer our customers a comprehensive set of products and related services, including implementation and integration services, and to reach a broad segment of customers. We may disclose personal information of certain customers to some of these partners, but only if the partners are working with us to provide products and services to those customers. Also, we only disclose personal information to partners who are under contracts that prohibit any further disclosure of that information and allow the partners to use the information only for purposes of providing Oracle products and services to our common customers.

**Oracle CustomerWorld and other partner co-sponsored events.** Oracle hosts a bi-annual event, called Oracle CustomerWorld, to explore the real issues you face every day in building your business around customers. When you register on one of our web sites to attend this event, we request certain information from you, such as your name, email address, company and industry. Because of Oracle's concern about the privacy of your personal information, however, and to give you the opportunity to make an informed choice as to whether or not it is shared with third parties, we tell you on the registration page that your registration information will be forwarded to Oracle's partners for certain limited purposes related to that event, and we give you an opportunity to tell us that you do not want your registration information forwarded to Oracle's partners. Also, any partner who receives registration information is contractually required to protect and hold this information in confidence, and may only use that information to invite our customers to meetings and other events hosted by the partner on-site at CustomerWorld. Oracle takes a similar approach whenever we co-host other events with partners.

**Co-branded web sites.** As mentioned above, Oracle operates co-branded web sites with two of our Global Strategic Alliance partners, Sun Microsystems and Hewlett Packard. These web sites include an overview of our alliance with each of these partners and information regarding the solutions available as a result of our relationship with each company. We may request personal information from you if you request certain information on these co-branded sites or ask us to contact you. This information is similar to the information we request when you register on [www.oracle.com](http://www.oracle.com/) or create a Siebel.com Passport, but also includes some additional information regarding your company. Any personal information provided through these web sites is collected and maintained by Oracle. We treat such personal information the same way we treat other personal information collected through our web sites and we would only disclose it to our partners under the circumstances described in the paragraph above entitled **"Oracle partners."**

### Choices Regarding Your Personal Information

At Oracle, we are committed to giving you a choice, whenever possible, as to how we use your information and with whom we share that information. When you create a Siebel.com Passport or other user profile on one of our web sites, for example, you can elect to receive information regarding our products, services, educational opportunities or special promotions by email, and to have a Oracle Advisor contact you by phone. You can always change your preferences by accessing your profile online and making the appropriate changes. Similarly, when you register for CustomerWorld or another Oracle event, we give you an opportunity to ask us not to share your personal information with our partners who work with us to sponsor those events.

Although Oracle makes every effort to protect your privacy and to give you a say in how we disclose your personal information, we may need to disclose personal information as required by law or when we believe such disclosure is necessary to protect our rights or to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on us. We also reserve the right to disclose personal information in connection with the sale or other transfer of all or part of our business, and to disclose personal information to law enforcement authorities upon request.

### Access to Your Personal Information

Any time you would like to see the personal information Oracle maintains about you, you can request a copy of such information. Simply send an email with "Personal Information Request" in the Subject line to [privacy_ww@oracle.com](mailto:privacy_ww@oracle.com). You can also receive this information by sending a letter to the address indicated at the end of this Privacy Statement. We will do our best to respond to your request within a reasonable time. At a minimum, we will contact you within 30 days to tell you approximately how long it will take us to fulfill your request.

**Changes to your personal information.** If your personal information changes and you would like to update the personal information in our records, please send an email requesting those changes to [privacy_ww@oracle.com](mailto:privacy_ww@oracle.com). Alternatively, you can send us your requested changes by mail to the address indicated below.

### Security

The security of your personal information is important to us. As a result, Oracle uses a number of generally accepted industry standard measures to protect against loss or unauthorized access to the personal information that has been provided to us. These measures include administrative policies and procedures, as well as technical safeguards. The technical safeguards we use include: 

  * Network security controls, which are defined and limited using network firewalls. All firewall rules are reviewed on at least a quarterly basis. 
  * Encryption, which Oracle uses as appropriate to protect sensitive information and other confidential data of the company. For example, as described above, we use SSL encryption to transmit credit card numbers we receive to our credit card processors. 
  * Physical entry controls, which we use to protect all secure areas that are owned or controlled by Oracle, including temporary locations. These controls are designed to prevent unauthorized access, damage to, or interference with the business processes that take place within those areas. 
  * System access controls, such as two-factor authentication, for all remote access to Oracle's corporate network, regardless of the source.

Unfortunately, no method of transmission over the Internet or method of electronic storage is completely secure; therefore, although Oracle strives to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personal information, it cannot guarantee its absolute security.

In the unlikely event that individual personal information has been acquired, or is reasonably believed to have been acquired, by an unauthorized individual and applicable law requires notification, Oracle will notify the affected customers of that breach. We will provide such notice promptly, although notification may be delayed if Oracle or any law enforcement agency determines that notification would hinder an investigation.

If you have questions about security on our web site, you may email us at [privacy_ww@oracle.com](mailto:privacy_ww@oracle.com).

### Key Oracle Products and Personal Information

**Siebel CRM On Demand.** Oracle also offers the fastest-growing hosted CRM application service - Siebel CRM On Demand. You can learn more about this exciting, cost-effective service at [www.crmondemand.com](http://www.crmondemand.com/). To provide this service, we may use one or more third party service providers to collect, process, store, or otherwise handle information on our behalf.

The Siebel CRM On Demand service involves three types of personal information: 

  1. Personal information provided by ad hoc visitors to [www.crmondemand.com](http://www.crmondemand.com/). Oracle collects and treats this information the same way as personal information collected through www.oracle.com or other Oracle web sites.
  2. On Demand User information. We collect and store personal information related to the users of the Siebel CRM On Demand service. We use this information for user authentication purposes and we generally treat this information the same way as personal information collected on www.oracle.com or other Oracle web sites. Users of the Siebel CRM On Demand service have a profile within the service, which they can use to change or update the personal information included within their profile. They can also use their profile to change their preferences regarding the manner in which we contact them, or to tell us we may not contact them for marketing purposes, by making appropriate changes on the user profile pages.
  3. Data stored on the Siebel CRM On Demand service by Oracle's customers, which may include personal information regarding their customers, employees, partners or others. Oracle does not access our customers' data stored on the CRM On Demand service, unless the customer grants explicit permission to do so. Such access may be established for trouble-shooting that is specific to that customer. Neither Oracle nor our hosting partners will use this personal information stored by our customers on the Siebel CRM On Demand service for marketing purposes or share this information with any other third party.

**Oracle EasyPay.** Oracle also offers Oracle EasyPay, a hosted product that enables our customers to integrate Web, Interactive Voice Response and customer service representative payment channels to accept one-time, recurring and scheduled payments via a wide range of payment instruments. In using Oracle EasyPay, our customers will store personal information regarding their customers, possibly including credit card information. The personal information stored by our customers in the Oracle EasyPay program is hosted by Oracle. All information transmitted into the program is encrypted using SSL encryption and credit card information is encrypted in our database where it is stored. Oracle will only access the information stored by a customer to provide that customer technical support for the Oracle EasyPay program. We do not use any information stored by our customers in the Oracle EasyPay program for marketing purposes. 

### Changes to this Privacy Statement

If we change our Privacy Statement in any material way, we will notify you here, by email or by posting a notice on www.crmondemand.com. You can be assured, however, that, since Oracle is a member of TRUSTe's Privacy Program, we would have to get any such changes approved by TRUSTe before we implement them.

### Contact Us

If you have any questions, comments, or concerns about this Privacy Statement or Oracle's privacy practices, please either send us an email to [privacy_ww@oracle.com](mailto:privacy_ww@oracle.com) or contact us at the following address:

Oracle Corporation  
Attn: Privacy and Information Security Office  
500 Oracle Parkway  
Redwood Shores, CA  
94065  
USA 

Effective Date: December 13, 2005 (date of TRUSTe certification)

|    

HOW IT WORKS

See Siebel CRM On Demand in Action   

PRODUCT TOURS
